Guide to the William H. Walter and George W. Walter Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II. George W. Walter, 1865-1913
  - Subseries II.1: Music Manuscripts, 1865-1913
    - Hymns, Anthems and Secular Music
      - Hark the Herald Angel Sing, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Papyrographed copy. (Two copies.))
      - Hark the Herald Angel Sing, 1884 December 24 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - The Horse and his Rider, 1866 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (The chorus from George Frideric Handel's Israel in Egypt arranged for the organ by G.W. Walter. Dedicated to "all true lovers of respectable music and especially to those who have to particular fondness for Vincent Novello's dirty stuff".
      - March of the Board of the Public Works, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Adapted from Tell This to the Marines.)
      - Our Lord is Risen From the Dead, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Procession in E, 1877 February 19 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Author's manuscript. For the organ.)
      - Procession in E, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (For the organ. Copied by Theodosia J. Walter.)
      - Procession in E, 1912 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Reverie, 1869 20 July (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Music by G.W. Walter and Words by H. Bayley. Dedicated to Josephine Starbuck.)
      - Reverie, 1869 14 August (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Author's manuscript. Music by G.W. Walter and Words by H. Bayley. Dedicated to Josephine Starbuck.)
      - Reverie, 1869 20 July (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Music by G.W. Walter and Words by H. Bayley. Dedicated to Josephine Starbuck. Copied by Theodosia J. Walter.)
      - Reverie, 1913 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Reverie, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Romanza, 1872 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (From Fromental Halev's L'éclair arranged for organ by G.W. Walter.)
      - The Silent Cry, 1885 September 25 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (From The Journal and Messenger.)
      - Sing Unto God, 1868 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (Vocal Score. Author's Manuscript. An anthem from the 68th Psalm, verses 31-35.)
      - Untitled, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
        (A loose page of music.)
    - Organ Books
      - Loose signatures, 1866 February 12-1872 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        (Loose signatures from an organ book.)
      - Loose signature, 1873 February 12-1873 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        (Loose signature from an organ book.)
      - Organ Book, 1894 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Subseries II.2: Publications, 1875-1900
    This sub-series contains George W. Walter's various publications, including books, sheet music, and pamphlets.
    - All Alone, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Gloria Patri, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      (Score)
    - Gloria Patri, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      (Tenor part.)
    - Gloria Patri, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      (Bass part.)
    - Gloria Patri, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      (Soprano part.)
    - Gloria Patri, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      (Alto part.)
    - Canticles of the Church Pointed for Chanting, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Festival Jubilate, 1881 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Shadow of the Rock, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Temple Organ, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Subseries II.3: Miscellaneous, 1870-1873
    This sub-series contains a scrapbook and George W. Walter's notes on hereditary genius.
    - Scrapbook, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hereditary Genius: an inquiry into its laws and consequences, 1870 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      (Excerpts from an essay by Francis Galton copied in G.W. Walter's hand with his analysis.
- Series III: David Palmer and James Cheetham, 1957-1967
  This series contains a subject bibliography about James Cheetham (grandfather of William H. Walter), an early 19th Century author, journalist and political activist. It also contains genealogical information on the Walter and Cheetham families, excerpts from books by James Cheetham, correspondence, and newspaper clippings as well as a single piece of music arranged by David Palmer.
  - James Cheetham-1772-1810 A Bibliography, 1803-1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    (Written by David Palmer. Contains a subject bibliography about James Cheetham, genealogical information on the Walter and Cheetham families, excerpts from books by James Cheetham, correspondence, and newspaper clippings.
  - James Cheetham-1772-1810 A Bibliography, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    (Only the subject bibliography is contained.)
  - Correspondence, 1967 March 23-May 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    (Correspondence between the Readex Microprint Corporation and David Palmer regarding the availability of The American Citizen newspaper.
  - Chorale, 1947 May 18 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    (Arranged for two pianos from Bach's Cantata No. 140 by David Palmer.)